Okay, we are going to call it a order, the regular meeting of the Miami City Council for today's date and time.
Item 2 is public input and unscheduled personal appearances.
Anyone that audits at which to address a council on any agenda item outside the public area you're going to have.
Any other agenda items anybody wants to discuss?
There are being non item 3 as a consent agenda staff if we're recommending items 4 through 8 for the consent agenda.
If there are a whole question on you those items, entertain the motion to approve as recommended.
Here I should point out.
I mean that's the word 2.
Okay.
And we have those, I guess we're going to be asked to sign those later.
Yeah.
So, Ben should we not approve those?
Well, that's the one.
Okay.
One of it.
So, approve.
Most of it.
Let's pull the minutes out.
So, we have a motion to approve the consent agenda with the exception of the minutes.
Yes.
I'll make that motion.
Second.
Go.
I.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
Now, the rules of the consent agenda is if you want to discuss an item you have to pull it out.
If there's any discussion about it also, we've pulled out the minutes.
Now, I would make a motion to approve the minutes with the two changes.
The minor changes that have been indicated and you'll be asked at the end of the meeting to sign revised minutes from the last thing.
So, do we have a motion to approve the minutes as recommended?
No.
As amended.
Yes.
I'll make it a second.
Second.
Go.
All right.
That takes us to item nine.
Public hearing concern the orders to rezone 2128.
The north-west of the planning area for the city of Miami as a planned view of development for research and development of the equipment needed to grow medical marijuana and research, grow and harvest medical marijuana in furtherance of such research and development.
And Christie, if you would start out with the refreshing airbodies of the memory of what a planned development is and the implications of that.
So, a planned unit development is a special design that we use that is specific, exactly specific to what's going on within the facility.
So, in this case, in actual zone, for these actual zoning, we've said that it is an exactly how it's working right here, that it is for the research and development of equipment needed to grow medical marijuana and research, grow and harvest,
medical marijuana in the furtherance of such research and development.
So, if at any point, Mr. Dangering decides to do so.
different from what is said on here, you will have to come back and
exhibit again to have that so we need adjusted right now.
And is the current activities is still active, the senior living facility?
No, sir.
Okay, close at the end of all this.
So then, so that would not be an ongoing purpose.
The sole purpose then would be as described.
Okay.
No, should please come up, I just want to just to offer some clarity to this.
We're wanting to lease a very, become evenly partnered with a, we want to lease a small
section of our facility to them or this purpose, which is why we've requested the UD.
I'm not going to be a large scale marijuana growing operation.
Their focus is around the equipment needed to grow the products indoors, lighting systems,
air filtration, water filtration, soil types, that's where they receive their funding from these
manufacturers.
Okay.
So their funding does not come from the sale of medical marijuana, it comes from the manufacturers
of these products and in return when the testing is over, they submit these results back to
these manufacturers that they use for publication.
Okay.
So the building's not set up to be a large scale marijuana growing operation.
However, it is set up perfectly to do what they're wanting to do, which is small scale testing
of these individual products because it has 18 individual rooms, most of them are less than
100 square feet, so it just gives you that ability to be able to do that.
So just so we were clear.
And again, it's a very small, we have 20 rooms in our facility, they're wanting at least five.
Okay.
So it's from their perspective, it's a very small operation.
What they do beyond our facility is entirely between them and the state and has nothing to do with me.
I just want to be clear that that's the focus of this facility that is not to turn out large quantities of cannabis.
And so the, I'm going to call them the vacant rooms.
They're just going to remain vacant, you have no business purpose that you're going to utilize those four.
No, we may utilize some office space, we have an office there, which will continue to be there.
So which is another reason why we went with the PUD zone.
If it was just going to be a, you know, we're just going to try to pump out as much marijuana as we could, then we would have to go industrial.
That was never the intention, then a war now.
So, but there, everything else in the facility will just be office next.
And I'm just trying to make clear, obviously, they're well represented by council.
And I know you and Christie have had lots of conversations, but you're defining this very precisely, which in a way ties your hands.
And that's okay.
And I just want to be clear.
Sure, now, with that being said, there will be marijuana grown in there.
Yeah, I don't, but the way I read this, that's fine.
Yes, yes, but as far as, again, a full-scale growing operation, that's not the intention.
It's not the intention of the company that's going to be releasing this from us.
Okay, so it will be up to us to make sure that we keep the reins on that.
And you know, and they only get a certain piece of our facility and nothing more.
Okay.
Question, Kristi, what is the, as far as the UD?
What type of UD does this fall under?
I mean, I know it's not a Kim, not a culture.
Well, I don't know.
So I'm not sure that there are different types of UD.
Everything UD is different.
Okay.
So we're still on the side of it.
Exactly.
As the mayor was just mentioning a little ago, a PUD is very directed towards the land use.
Right.
So there's not a PUD for commercial.
Okay.
President and say, is specific PUD allowing this type of use to be used on that property?
There's a PUD have to fall within the broader zoning of an area.
Or is it an effect of rezoning?
Does it affect medical marijuana grown in your residence?
I know that we passed an ordinance that says, you just like the swimming pools as high as explained.
You can't have any front yard.
You've got to have to be in close.
They have to be in close.
But you don't have to rezone your property then.
You just have to have the license.
Right.
So this is more for research not for growing and selling.
That's correct.
That's not to say that the by-product won't be marketed somewhere.
No.
That's also correct.
That the company will inevitably sell the product to further their research on these products that they're testing from these manufacturers.
None of those proceeds come to me.
They're paying me a lease to be here.
And that's it.
So what they do with that product once it's harvested is entirely up to them.
These are physicians.
Okay.
They're not.
They're not concerned about the two or three pounds of marijuana that they might produce from these facilities.
The vision is much larger because this industry is not going to go away.
I think we've all determined that.
Okay.
So there.
This will be the only one of these facilities in the state.
The research and development around these products.
There's not enough.
So they're kind of trying to get this off at the ground somewhere in this area.
And where it goes from there.
It's nice to be seen.
It's not the only one in this state for licensing reasons.
It just happens to be the only one in the state at this time.
That's correct.
The licensing is the same.
They still have to apply for a commercial grow versus license.
Okay.
It's no different than if they were going to be growing 20,000 plants in a warehouse.
The licensing from the state's view is the same.
They're intentions, however or not.
And on that note, there's nothing that precludes a commercial going license in this area if we zone it this way.
So our current ordinance has specific zoning employees from different rural areas.
And anybody that in, and so it's industrial, it's an inquiry.
If you want to be a rural worker based on the current, the zoning that you guys just passed, it has to be located in an inquiry industrial area.
Anybody could decide, well, I don't want to go to an industrial area.
I want to locate, you know, on South May, in the commercial area.
They could apply for a key to be to zone, we would, we would make it a key to be.
We would say, we won't zone it in industrial, if you want to go before we're fighting,
Commission and the Council to try to resound that, so you can grow.
Medical marijuana, then they, you would say, instead of your community, and you have that right.
We would turn it down as the city of the first hand, and then they would appeal it to the paying commission and then from there.
And you would turn it down for what reason?
Because it was a commercial establishment, so they had a commercial business.
This is just a simple example.
Right.
But anybody can apply for a key to grow.
Mental marijuana in any.
Anywhere.
So we are establishing a precedent outside of our, the zoning that we've got currently established.
I think I, I don't think so.
I think this is a research facility for products that aiding marijuana for life extras, air filters.
Different things like that.
It's not a full-eyed, broad operation.
They're not making the money on sale to grow and sell and medical marijuana.
So even though it requires the same type of licensing, which is a commercial license, the new dry distinction between someone that's growing it commercially for profit versus research.
I might add, Mayor, that we did in the ordinance, we do have a provision for research facilities.
But that was aimed at research on the marijuana.
This operation is for research on the equipment with which to grow the marijuana.
And that, I think, is their distinction.
Essentially, you could look at it as both because part of their, part of their research is which products are the most successful.
In the end of the day, they are going to be sampling that product and taking samples from each individual rooms to determine which of those products produced the most yield, which ones have the healthiest plants, which one groom the fact.
Okay, so ultimately it is going to be about the plan at the end of the day, but that research is around us products.
Just want to clarify.
The other thing I was going to say, the state bill that just went in force on the 29th.
Say that again.
The state bill, the unity bill, just went in to effect on August 29th.
And I also requires people that have licenses to get certificates of occupancy on where you know.
So Mr. Dammer is just now getting into this.
And so he has to have a certificate of occupancy from us saying that the building is up to code,
but it's only properly and all of that.
Everyone else that has been in business prior to now will have to get that upon the renewal.
And then every year after that, when they renew their license, we go in and that's not apply again.
So that's also our way of going in and making sure that the zoning is still what's happened.
Okay.
Any other questions?
Any concerns?
This equipment you're going to be developing is they going to be patented.
Yes, we'll seek patents for this.
Most of it already is.
It's already patented.
Yes.
I don't give you some examples.
There's three lighting companies.
Most of the stuff that we, they are wanting to test is all LED.
Okay, because historically speaking, people who grow medical marijuana indoors,
they use high pressure sodium lighting.
Okay, it's extremely hot, draws a lot of power.
So a lot of the researchers around LED light.
What LED lights on the market are the best of the best.
So you've got companies like Spectrum King and Black Dog and Viper Spectrum.
Okay, they're making these LED lights that they claim will yield as much marijuana as a high pressure sodium light.
That's what they're wanting to test.
Will they, in fact, do that.
And if they will, which ones really are the leader of the industry?
Some of these are extremely expensive.
One of the Black Dog lights is $2,500.
Okay, and you need four to five of those in every room.
So if put that in perspective, it's very expensive to purchase these.
Some of these manufacturers have an offer significant discounts for this information.
This data would be provided back to them after testing this complete,
because they use it to further their R&D.
Okay, so.
So yes.
Okay.
I know we use a lot of LEDs in a push to convert everything.
But you know, then initial costs and so high that it's called for him.
Thank you.
Anyone else in the audience?
I want to be hearing the public hearing portion.
And the other comments or questions are concerned.
So the reasoning is actually really just going to affect five or six rooms currently.
But long-term is that any aesthetic perspective occurred?
It's such a terrible thing.
Of the entirety of, okay, everything in the room.
Right, but I'm saying right now, they're only utilizing that many rooms.
So down the road, there could be growth that would take place there.
Potentially, we don't anticipate that now.
They have not led to the lead.
Let us believe that there is going to be any growth.
As of now, the only area that they're going to occupy is this north wing right here.
There's five rooms and then a common area in this north wing of the building.
And that's all there to win the archive.
And on another note that I just thought I would throw out there.
You know, a lot of people have concerns about the odor.
Okay, when you're growing that, when we're a water.
That's actually one of the products that they're testing.
That's carbon filtration.
All of our rooms are been it.
Because of the way the building was set up before they all have exhaust fans.
Every room has an exhaust fan.
So there'll be a carbon filter system on every one of these exhaust fans
that when that air is pulled out of the building,
by the time it reaches the root flood of that building, there will be no odor left.
Okay, so that's just another one of the products that we're going to be testing there.
It's various types of carbon filtration.
You just sucked that odor out of the air before it's set outside.
Hey, we're going to close the public hearing portion of the meeting.
And we're going to move on to item 10, which is the actual ordinance to resume 2128 B.
Northwest.
As a plan year, development for the research and development of equipment,
need to grow medical marijuana, research, grow harvest medical marijuana,
and programs of such research and development.
Do we have a motion to approve the ordinance?
And it was recommended by staff if I remember reading correctly.
Motion to approve.
Do we have a second?
A second.
Roll call.
Western.
Hi.
Louis.
I work it.
Hi.
I don't know.
Well, the heart of state from the reading of the statute,
where you said it was the emergency call.
The clause is enacted today.
There's going to be a 30, 30 day time in the point that forms to come to effect it.
I think they would like to get started as soon as possible.
So at that standpoint, yes, we'd like that.
Is there really?
I mean, obviously, is there really an emergency that exists?
I don't think there's a emergency exists.
Other than it's important to them to be able to get started on the operation.
Ben, do you have any concerns about the enacting an emergency clause?
We just asked that out before.
Okay. So I'll make a motion to approve the emergency clause. Do we have a second?
Roll call, please.
Short sign.
Work it.
All right.
Lewis, I question.
Thank you.
Item 12's contract.
Item 12's actually were in table that item.
I would think all of you have a copy of the proposed contract.
And I'll be in the main couple of minor changes.
Maybe it's in the other version.
So if you please take time between now and the next meeting to review that and
that.
And I know Marsha.
Brian has some questions.
He's not here tonight.
And Marsha's going to follow up.
I think he responded those.
And email everybody.
That fair to say.
Great.
Item 13.
I'm a county property dedication to the city of my own.
The following property is 227.
B.
And 292.
Even.
227.
B.
And 229.
And he was resident in the council.
The idea.
Letting these properties go back to the county and the tax sell.
And then the city's working to kick those properties that.
This was in September of 2018.
And they did go back to the county and the tax sell.
And we discussed with the county, the city taking those properties.
And they agreed to that there.
Here in this square.
There's actually.
for our five structures on this square of property right here.
Our plan is that if you agree to accept the property from the county,
is to go in and dim up those structures.
To date, well, at the time that we did the September presentation,
the city had invested, like $8,000 in mowing and boarding and securing,
and all the things that come along with why the properties that people need behind.
And so we would like to take the properties, dim up the structures that are on there.
Level it, get it ready to market and try to market those as an economic development
and business to locate.
And what you point out that Volvo, the address is on B,
then actually that property front you on Steve Olin, right?
This property front is on Steve Olin's, this is on B.
Okay.
And we make contact with Charlotte and told her about the properties in what our plan is by the time.
By the time we're done with the demo and everything, the city will have invested about $20,000 in this,
and that makes a nice incentive for someone to look at on a busy street here and laying around.
So, you're looking for a motion to accept the properties from the county.
Yeah, but the wording that we've used in the past is for the dedication of these properties.
Okay.
We think it'll cost a demo of those.
My estimate is that it will probably cost about seven, oh well, it depends on if there's
a specific amount, but it could be up to 10,000.
By the time a piece, so it would be like 10,000 for these two,
10,000 for those, possibly, that it really, it just depends on what's in that up to
the votes on it.
They both had utilities at one time.
Yeah.
That's a nice.
Have you had a nice conversation?
Yeah.
So, do we have a motion to approve the dedication of the properties of okay, the 227 and 229 being
southeast?
I'll make that motion.
And a second please?
Second.
We'll call.
Louis?
I.
Okay.
Short.
All right.
Thanks, Chris.
You got a 14 memorandum understanding between the city of Miami and visit Bartelsville,
Amanda?
Basically, what we have is you guys will remember to give a cruise at 10 to the last year for us
or in the M.A. use for the travel center.
So, visit Bartelsville has approached us and in a full four quarters, they're requesting that only
two quarters.
They're wanting to do the first quarter and the third quarter.
So, we kind of experienced this over the last 12 months or so, we've had a pretty
up and down year with hotel tax and what we're starting to see as some of these other communities
that weren't experiencing that, it's starting to cycle through to them.
So, this is just coming before you guys tonight because the original template did not give an option
for it to be by quarter, it was for basically the entire.
And what are they getting in return?
So, it's in your packet.
So, basically what they get is for each quarter, they have a canvas that's up on the wall.
We do some additional marketing for them as part of the travel center.
They have rotating photos that are up on a TV monitor, some of visitors come in, they can see
pictures of what our community that is.
We do tracking, which you guys have that in your packet as well, that shows the referrals, that
are staff, that's sentient to different communities.
And then we also give them the breakdown.
So, somebody comes in from, you know, out of state, and I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
It's guy, you guys know what I went through yesterday.
I was waiting on that call.
I asked you to appreciate that for a little bit.
It's been nice working.
We're not a little bit.
Not a little bit, we haven't had a pretty big room.
We're all okay, but it was already in the past.
So, we're waiting on that call for guy, though.
That will be where it works tomorrow.
Well, the reason I ask you is, realistically, are you going to stop doing those things
in the second fourth quarter?
Yeah.
And I express that to her.
I feel really like to see you, everybody else has made a commitment, but I also met with
our budget out there.
I'd really, brother, take $25,000, $25,000, and it's still off to those services for two
quarters, then to tell them that we wouldn't be interested in that.
Do we have a motive?
We also hope that things get better than we'll go back to the fourth quarter as well.
Yeah.
Do we have most to approve the amount of understanding between my and my and my and my and my
and my and my.
Are you just revising that template or are you going to revise all of them?
Well, I'm not suggesting that you'd give them the option, but I didn't know if you
had a template.
Well, they actually changed the template.
They actually went in and marked out the original template, and then just put in $13, so I guess
really were just approving.
Okay.
So we have a motion to approve the revised template between city of my and my and my and visit
borders real.
Seven.
And a second.
Second.
We'll call please.
Work it.
All right.
Louis.
Aye.
West.
So.
Aye.
Thanks, Amanda.
Item 15.
We're going to 20 not to 2019 dash 10 and minute chapter 21.
That's in 21.26 regarding excavations, row, row, boy, street cuts, it's set.
No, we talked about this a little bit last meeting.
Talk about it again.
You go.
You always.
For a long time, we've required a permit for any contractor to dig up or under any of our
roads or sidewalks allies.
And it has no teeth in the present ordinance.
So this is a proposal that would allow for a number of different ways of enforcing the ordinance.
The main problem we have is we do have contractors that will come in, they'll do work in an
alley, for instance, and we don't know a thing about it, and then we have to go back in after
the fact and fix the alley up so that it's somebody can drive through there.
And so this is intended to get their attention and make sure they understand they need to do
this, we have provisions in there that if they ignore the ordinance as they have in the past,
that it could keep them from getting other licenses.
or permits from the city, okay?
Any questions that have been a rubber,
and we talked about this a little bit last time.
Do we have most to improve out in 16,
or it's 2019-11, most improved?
And a second.
A second.
Cool, cool.
Less than five.
Who is I?
Work it.
Sure.
I need 17.
I'll rub it.
I'm 17, do you business?
I'll just get, no.
16.
All right, so we've already approved the wrong item.
So we've got most of the approved item 15,
which is over the 2019-10.
Most of the approved item.
And I'll still second.
We'll roll with you.
All right.
I'll work it.
Should we?
Now let's discuss the item we've already approved.
Don't know if that's the only solution.
That's a question.
Actually, it's a VN.
I just told you.
That's why I set up.
You said 20, right?
It's a natural method.
This is the same effort.
It provides that if somebody is violating our building codes and contractors,
regularly violating our building codes, or violates our flood ordinances,
or violates our now-are-street-cutting ordinance.
But any of those can all be considered insofar as issuing permits and licenses in the future.
Tell me any questions.
Let's just approve it once more for them.
We have an option to approve.
I'll second it.
I'll in favor.
A roll call.
Question.
Louis, aye.
Orcate.
Aye.
I'm sorry.
I'm saying there's new other new business.
Any of these things?
I'm making a staff report.
So there's the practice.
I'm going to ask about what we have questions.
I think 19 is there and council committee in Auschwitz.
We have any announcements.
We have the designs of autumn fall festival.
This week starting Thursday with the Crab Boyle.
And continuing with music and a movie in the downtown park.
And sidewalk sales is all kind of just said,
but he began just seven years first.
Any other announcements.
Did you go to the game this weekend?
May.
I had a great time.
I've got to go home.
Three cotton morning.
I took a shortcut.
I'm going to send a message on communications.
Just very quickly just to confirm that we're going to have a special meeting a week
from tomorrow on September 11.
And we've all agreed that we can try to make it at 4pm so 4.30 is we originally talked about it
last week.
So, we'll have you off.
to double check with Brian on that conference.
Well, but if we can get that credit ordinance passed, that would help.
OK.
And we have submitted the ordinance to the global water resources
award in FEMA.
FEMA did want a couple of minor changes.
Those have been done and submitted back to them.
OK.
I don't believe they have been sent out to you.
Nothing in substance.
Yes.
It's a business that we need to practice.
But it sent to the council members.
No, not just my idea.
OK.
Sorry.
No.
Nothing major.
OK.
Item 21 is adjournment.
Do we have a motion to adjourn?
OK.
Do we have a second due?
Well, call.
Work in.
What's in?
All right.
Lovis.
I'll kill.
Hi.